Hey guys, welcome back. In this video, we will see the dynamic link libraries. Basically,
we will call it as a DRL files, and this DRL file will be used by the attack post to
deliver their malware successfully into the update system, into the Windows machines, which
are running all the dark, okay. Let's take an example of DRL first. Then we will go
for an API's. So, in a previous video, you see there is a cross executable file, EXE file.
So, you can see the magic value 45A and M is it. So, the DRL file, it's like a library
file, okay. Basically, we will say this file as a PE file, only not a CR any other programming
file. We will call it this as a PE file only, but this kind of DRL has an important export
function. So, let you let take an example of you are going to develop one of browser
application and the browser application needs to communicate with the internet, right.
So, you need to face loss, loss, you need to face more challenges when you are developing
that code, right. So, because you have to implement a lot of protocols and functions to
use that, okay. But what Microsoft did, Microsoft created the custom DRLs and they placed
in the OS system folders like Windows system that you do. So, you need to use the DRL,
okay. So, this is a simple way, they already created a DRL for you, already created every
functions every code for you. So, you need to use that DRL and functions and you can
develop a simple browser application, okay. So, if there is a, if you need to develop
a browser application with a thousand lines of code. So, if Microsoft has that custom
DRLs that has been already placed on the Windows 32, so your code will be reduced to
300 or 400 lines, okay. So, the Microsoft already contains all the codes and function,
you need to use that code in your program, that's all, okay. So, that's called a dynamic
link library files, that's a library files, we are using that library files for our application
for several functionalities, okay. So, let me give a few examples, there is a kernel 32.0
DRL, that has been under the system 32 folder. So, this DRL has a function to read a memory,
write a memory and creating a space in the memory and every APA function, APA functions,
we have, okay. So, the next we have a AD, the APA 32.0 DRL. So, if you want to encrypt
any data in your machine, so this DRL will be there, so if you want to develop a software
applications like that needs to encrypt your data manually, you can use this DRL, you don't
need to manually code everything, you can use this DRL and you can use the DRL functions
and you can code it, okay. And if you need to develop a dose application, you have a URL
on, so you have a URL on DRL will help you to downloading the files, uploading the files,
web compressions, working with URLs, every, every, every, everything, okay. So, you don't need to do
much but Microsoft created everything and you have to use that program and you can develop
your own application, so that will be easy. So, every, every, system programmers needs to understand,
they have a idea about this kind of DRL's present in the Microsoft, okay.
So, let's take a simple example of DRL first, let's, let's get on to the Windows machine and we'll
go for a Windows. Let's find the system 34, and here you can see a lot of files, there is a lot
of DRL will be placed here, let me search for kernel, so you can see there is a kernel 30 to
DRL lost here, we already discussed, right. So, let we will pull this DRL into the T loader, let me
create another, let me load another explorer and we will load our DRL inside our DDR and we will
see how the DRL will be for the format of the DRL's and all, okay. Let's take, let's load the kernel
this DRL, kernel 30 to DRL, let's place the DRL into our DDR. So, today you have seen the
similar kind of data in the exe file, you can see the same data with the emissive format, I already
said the DRL is also an executable file, so it will be in the emissive and the magic numbers will
be 4D and 5A of that and we have another headers and the empty header as you can see it's
pointing to the PE portable executable format and we have seen a text section, resource section,
what are the things we have basically, okay. So, let's go through the import and export functions,
present in the DRL's, we can see a lot of functions here and a lot of exports and import
functions from here, okay. So, this all are the functions which will be used for several things,
so you can see create a job object, create something, something create process, we need to use this
scalar when you need to create a process, create remote thread of, so we'll go for more interesting,
alphabet and we will see something of nothing in the V,
let's take an example, don't go for a V, let's take an example of another functions like
create object or create a remote thread of, so there's a create remote thread, let's let's
research something about the create remote thread, we'll go for a booger and let's go into the
malati.io, so if this is the repository, this contain a lot of a lot of functions, present under
the DRL, okay, it's basically we can say it's an APA functions, so it give a information about the
APA function, okay, so let's take a real example here, you can see a create remote thread of
function will be there, so in the same way you can see the injection, so here you can see the create
remote thread, so the create remote thread will be used to create a thread, rinse in a virtual
address space of an another process, so we can learn more about this create remote thread
of in the upcoming sessions, so there's a lot of lot of lot of lot of APAs that will be used
for a malware development, so you can see everything from each and everything from here, so let's go
for a virtual a lock, so this APA function which I have searched, this will be used to allocate some
memory for a process, okay, whenever you double click on any of the application, though the
application will be load inside the memory, right, so you need to allocate some memory, allocate
some space in the memory, right, so you'll be using the virtual a lock of function, so the kernel
32 will be loaded, this library will be loaded, this library contains this functions, so this
function will be used for allocating some space inside the memory, CPU or hot is whatever you can
say, or RAM, okay, so after all allocating allocation only, you can load the load your process inside
the memory, right, so that's all our explanations of the virtual, I just searched this
virtual a key example, nothing there, I was just checking this virtual a lock here, so function
whether we can, in the statements, let's go to the import function, so import section there we have
nothing much, but in a export section only we have a lot of things, okay, so export section is like
we are, so if any of the applications need to use our functions, like create a remote thread of,
they can able to use that we can export that functions to the applications, okay, so import
is like we are importing something from some of the application and we are using that for further
features and further stuff, okay, doing some other things, yeah, yeah, here you can see there is a
virtual a lock, virtual a lock, virtual a lock and virtual a lock, the X of present under here, right,
so this is the overall explanation for what the DL will be contained and again I'm saying that
text section contain all the codeings which needs to be executed, so let's develop our
own DLR land we will see how to develop our own DLR, let's load our columnation,
so this is the very simple example of developing a developing your own DLR, so one more thing you
need to understand the DLR files or so if you want to execute the DLR files, so you can't able
to execute the DLR file, let me click on any of the DLR's like q5, qT5 is it, so it will not load, okay,
it will not load basically, it will not execute, we can't able to execute this DLR blindly,
so when you are loading the PEBR, okay, so let's see here I am loading the PEBR, so this PEBR will
use the qT5 it just dot DLR, so this PEBR will use the code present inside the qT5 it just dot DLR
and it will load the applications, okay, we can't blindly execute the DLR files by double
click on the Windows machine, okay, but we have an several other ways, the malware
threat tactics will be used, other ways to execute the DLR, I will be discussing that in the
in this video only, okay, so if I place this DLR in, if I cut and paste this DLR in some
other folders like q5, it's your turn, now if I try to load the PEBR, my PEBR will not be load
or because it was saying some DLRR will be missed, right, so I just placed it into the
pictures session, so let me replace that, come here to here, so now my application will be
normally get built, now load it, okay, so this is the way the Windows application will
use the DLR for further purpose, okay, if you want to develop any other programs,
any other application for Windows, you need to use the DLR for that, so absolutely we are also
using the DLR, for our malware development, okay, so let's play with
our own DLR, we have, we have a, we learned everything about the DLR, okay, this is a simple
program which we have developed, and this is the entry point of the DLR, run message
box DXC, instead of message box you can say, say it will display just a hello world, okay,
so you can develop a DLR in several ways, but I just developed the DLR with the entry point,
so this is the entry point for the DLR, so if you need to execute the DLR, you need to call
the entry point of the function like any APA functions, so this is the APA function, so I already
said, so if your application needs to communicate or any, or allocating any virtual space
instead of memory, you need to use several APA functions like virtual EX, this is like that,
this is the function of the entry point, we will say this is the entry point after DLR, so if you
need to execute this DLR, you need to call the entry point, manually, so that the attack
this will do like that, I will explain that in the same video, so let this, it will just
display the hello from DLR, okay, just it will not return any much things, so it will be,
under the, it will be, the files are under the videos, but we will do one thing, we will save
this file in some other directory like music, but to reduce our confusion, CPP, hello,
let me rename this as a fellow test dot, CPP, let's save up program in the music folder,
let's go to the music and we'll open a terminal here, else we'll go for videos,
and let's see, redirect to the music folder, so now you can see the CPP file
was present under the folder, let's compile this, so you can use the, this compiler to compile
the DLR files, so our DLR will be this, the, online, this DLR file which I hosted before,
though, don't worry about that, okay, so hello test, our DLR file will be the hello test, right,
test dot CPP, and we need to save the DLR, so hello test dot DLR, so let's execute this now,
you can see our DLR was executed, compile, sorry, compile, so now you can see the hello
test dot DLR was present here, let me go to the Windows machine and we will,
or give me a second, let me, yeah, so better, let me will copy this DLR into the server folder,
give me some time, I was unable to open the folders from here, so I just will copy from here,
by the command itself, our WWW, HTML, name it as a, hello test dot,
let me run with a, you dummy, yeah, Udemy course, hello test dot DLL,
so I think now the hello test dot DLL will be copied there, let me go through the Windows machine,
and we will, and we will see that, my IP address will go nine to 12 once, say dot 18 dot
3 slash, you dummy course, our DLR was there, hello test dot DLL, let's download this file,
it is file, so now our DLR hello test dot DLL will be placed in the download folder, let's
load up here, and we will investigate this DLL, little bit one does, and everything about the DLL,
well, I already said DLL, we have a entry find, right, it has a several functions,
so let's load DPE and load a DLC how creator, let's go to, uh,
import table or export exports, when I can see the run message box, there is only one functions,
name run message box, of their, and uh, this the strings, okay, after DLL, I already said the
test, uh, session contain the code, hello from DLL, everything was there, which we have developed,
let's, uh, let's execute this DLL, well, I already mentioned, if you want to execute a DLL,
you need a executable file, right, some exe file need to call the DLR need to,
but the title will do it in a different way, they have a different approach, so we already know,
there is a entry point of the DL, uh, so the entry point of the DLL was a run message box, we
are discussed that program, we discussed that program previously, right, so we can use one of the
tools that was involved in, uh, windows called, uh, run DL32.exe, so the run DL32.exe basically
has features, functionalities to execute a DL, uh, file, okay, so let's call the run DL30 to dot exe,
so you can see there's no errors get popped up, let me execute this fellow test,
dot DLL, so I already said if you want to execute a DLL using the run DL30 to dot exe,
you need to know the, you need to know the entry point from the DLR, right, if, uh, we know the
entry point will be the run message box here, but threat tactics will do the same, they will
develop a DLL and they are developing a DLL, so they, uh, so they have a entry point of the DL,
so they will execute the DLR with an entry point, okay, so our entry point is a run message box,
I'm doing the same run message box, so this is the way the threat tactics will execute the DLL,
uh, in a suspicious way inside the target host, okay, so now you can see, so our hello from DLL,
so which we have written that has been called, okay, so threat tactics plays a malicious code
instead of hello from DLL and they will execute the DLL by using the process run DL32.exe, okay,
so this is the, uh, overall explanation of the DLL, we have already cost 21 minutes,
so we will see you guys in the next section, sorry, next video,
bye, so we have completed the DLL, uh, things, I hope you have cleared about that,
yeah, see you, bye,